welcome back
today we are going to adventure in the mystical world of the UV tier quests
last time we rushed a UV Energy hatch
but we didn't complete any quest that wasn't strictly necessary
so today we are going to fix that
the main issue is that
those parts require a lot of motors
that contain a lot of americium
right now our only source of that material
is a single fusion reactor Mark 2
which can allow for a motor worth of material every half hour
we could make a second reactor to double the speed
but that would use up a lot of precious materials
also making americium in that way requires lutetium
and the way we are making it is
as waste of our nuclear reactors
which make a total of about 800 pieces every 10 hours
and so far
we have already used about one third of what we had stocked up since when our plant started its operation
there are other ways of making lutetium
but
I think we should just aim at the better way of making americium
fusion Mark 3
so going back to our quest
I think we are just going to wait a little bit more
to stock up the materials to do that quest
in the meantime
we can do some other quest
such as Kevlar
Kevlar is the next tier of plastic which will be required later on
and is made by a chain of a lot of machines
and in the four hours it took to build that thing
we managed to also craft the motors required to complete the UV components quest
next we need an assembler
but we now use the overvolted multi block one
now we have to show the energy hatches we already made last time
we could craft some more in advance
or we can just borrow one
next we can borrow our water purification plant
and with that
I think we can now move on to the fun parts of this mod pack
we are now going to start working with computation and glass fibers
starting from a quantum computer
which you can see built here
its size can be increased to have up to 24 racks
but for now 6 will be enough
other than the usual maintenance issues
this machine will also have uncertainty issues
to fix those issues
we have to use an uncertainty resolver
where we will have to balance the bleeping intensity of some squares in a grid
next we have to give power to that machine
it will need one UV amp of power for every rack
and one amp for the computer itself
that is 7 UV amps which is 28 zpm amps
so we use a 64 amps zpm hatch
once we connect the power lines
we can turn on our computer
however it looks like it is still unable to compute
and that is because we didn't insert any processor inside its racks
once we insert a vent and a bunch of processors
we turn it on
and here we can see how much computation we are producing
and the processor's temperature
and at some point something weird happened
our CPUs somehow melted
and it looks like something has indeed changed on how you should set up this machine
for the moment
we are not going to thinker with overclocks
so we just figure out something that works
we shall start with one vent and one crystal processor mainframe
the heat rapidly raises
but the hotter it gets the better the vent works
however
we used only half of the rack spaces
when we are paying for the full rack
so let's fill it up with the new better vents and one more main frame
after some time
it looks like the temperature stabilized close to the maximum temperature for those processors
and we are not even using the best cooling system
we could try for a better setup
but we are generating enough computation for the moment
also nowadays
the computer uses 1/4 of the power it used to eat
anyways we are now producing computation
but it is being wasted
since nothing is connected to the optical connector
so time to work on the first machine that will put that computation to good use
the research station
to use it
we place a data stick inside the controller
and the item we want to research inside the object holder
and now
we just have to wait for the research to be completed
and the research we are doing is going to take quite a lot of computation and power
but after a long wait
we managed to complete our research
we take that data to the assembly line databank
so that we can craft the new item we just unlocked
but while that new component is quite useful
it is not really helping us do any progress
we were going to work on Mark 3 fusion
but the correct way is probably
to start doing some advanced biochemistry
we start by making a new chain of machinery
to produce some Agar
and one other chain to produce some bio chaff
and to get all the plant, meat and bone required
we use some fishing ports
now that we have the materials
we can start brewing some random bacteria out of those things
we move into the clean room with those mundane bacteria
where using a bio lab
we start separating inside some petri dishes different variety of bacteria
now to use those cultures
we will want to place the petri dishes inside a bacterial vat
to make the bacteria multiply
a bacterial vat is a multi block with two main mechanics
to work at the best efficiency
you want to keep under check the bacteria population and the radiation levels
since we want to make lot of bacteria at low cost
we will want to make vats with wall shared radio hatches
the other mechanic is that we will want to keep the output hatch half filled
to maximize the bacteria growth
to do that we will have a cover that
once the hatch reaches half of the capacity
will turn on a pump to extract the new bacteria that is now in excess
and to quickly set up all of the vats
we can use a cover copy/paste tool
and with the base completed
we can also build the rest of the multi vat structure
one other issue is that
to keep the radiation level constant in the vat during the bacteria growth
we will be consuming up radioactive material
for this stage we are using bismuth
which lasts 3 minutes and we have in huge amounts
however for later stages
we will be using stuff such as an naquadria
which only lasts 8 seconds
and is a material we will not want to waste
so to avoid wasting radioactive materials
we are going to only input the radioactive stuff
when all of the other hatches are filled with the material required for the bacteria growth
and with later stages that will also grow in size
while the materials will get more expensive
and thus more easily depleted
and now that everything is ready
we can start cultivating bacteria
initially
they will have to spread out just from the petri dish
but once they start growing inside the machine
the more we have the faster they will grow
until the space inside the machine will start becoming too much populated
and before they start starving
the Redstone circuit will trigger the pump to extract the excess
and the next stage will be
to feed those normal bacteria with other stuff to the over evolutionized bacteria
which will then produce raw growth catalyst medium
but those bacteria is a really slow one to grow
so to make it grow faster
we are going to momentarily replace the machine hatch with a smaller one to stock up some fluid
that we will replace into the bigger hatch
for more fine regulation
and with that
we have the fluid required to produce stem cells
which we scan to obtain the instructions on how to build a neural processing unit
meanwhile using a lot of expensive materials
we can also start preparing some circuit boards capable of hosting life
which are also part of the neural processing boards
now since we are going to need a lot of those
to speed up the process
we can use a dedicated advanced assembly line
which is basically an assembly line
that will start a crafting before it has even finished the previous one
then we move to a new set of circuit assembly line
where we build our new wetware circuits
and here the research station comes into play
since it is required to craft the wetware mainframe
and this was one way faster research than last time
and with that
we can start building our new tier of circuits
the wetware main frames which are UHV tier
and we will use those right away to make UV field generaters
for the fusion reactor Mark 3
but once again
we have been stopped by the speed of our Mark 2 reactor
so we have to find something else to do while we wait
we shall start by preparing the americium wafers
those take just a pinch of americium
but the cooking time is extremely high
one other thing we can do is gather some mysterious crystal rich stone
and this is the actual mining speed
of our new adamantium alloy hammer and quantum legging running speed
next we can go fight some bosses
such as the sequel of the Ender Dragon
which will drop some stuff that might be useful later on
and it looks like harvesting that stuff caused some weird thing to happen
then after disrupting this island
we can run away
all the way to Pluto
where we fail at trying to tame a space dog
whom was hiding some rocket schematic in his nest
this time we are going to scan this schematic
this will yield a way of creating copies of it
since we are going to need a couple more later on
in the meantime
our americium boule is ready
thus, we can cut it using the water that survived absolute zero and helium plasma temperatures
and we are going to use those wafers
to slowly make quantum power integrated circuits
which are required for the upcoming reactor
which now misses only one thing to be completed
americium
while waiting for it
we can build a couple of PCB factories
those will make circuit boards cheaper and quicker than an LCR
or at least they will when we will equip the overclock and parallelization upgrades
for now
it will run on 22 EU per tick while on ZPM voltage
also we can even get bonus outputs at the cost of speed
and that's why we have a second PCB factory
for the more expensive circuits
but that is something we will really notice only
once we will be doing Bioware circuits in the next tier
and now
while waiting for the remainder of the americium
we can appreciate a couple of sunsets
but that didn't help us much
so I guess it is time to give up our indium
and do what we should have done one episode ago
a second fusion reactor Mark 2
now instead of taking an unbearable amount of time
it will only take a really really long time
so we can go watch some more sunsets
and after a long the wait
we have finally completed our new fusion reactor
which will start making americium in greater amounts as soon as it's charged up
however this recipe has a small issue
we are not getting americium but americium plasma
to get americium
we could either use a vacuum freezer which will use power
a heat exchanger which is a hassle
or we can run the plasma through a multi block turbine
which will produce americium as waste
however americium plasma has a huge energy density
meaning that the conversion will be rather slow
unless we use a huge turbine with a huge flow
but we are still limited by the dynamo hatch
anyways
what did we learn in today episode
yes we must always burn a lot of thorium in nuclear reactors during the early game
so we won't get stuck by lack of lutetium
and with that
I think we can close the episode
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要去 UV 电压的神秘世界探索一番
上一集速通了 UV 能源仓
但没有完成非必要的任务
所以今天我们要解决这个问题
主要问题是
这些零件需要大量的马达
也就是大量的镅
现在唯一的镅来源
是单个聚变反应堆 Mk-II
它每半小时产出一个马达的量
我们可以再来一个使速度加倍
但那会消耗很多珍贵的材料
用这种方式制造镅也需要镥
而我们获得它的方式
是作为核反应堆的副产
每 10 小时大约 800 个
到目前为止
已经用了开机以来差不多三分之一的库存
还有其他的方法来制造镥
但是
使用更好的方式来制作镅才是焦点所在
也就是聚变反应堆 Mk-III
所以回到任务
我想得再等一会儿
来准备好任务所需的材料
同时
可以做一些其他的任务
比如凯夫拉线
凯夫拉是之后会用到的下一级塑料
需要一长串的机器来制作
在造它的四个小时里
我们做出了完成 UV 组件任务所需的马达
接下来需要一台组装机
我们已经在用升压的多方块组装机了
现在只要把做过的能源仓拿出来秀秀
我们可以再多做一些
或者是借一个
接下来我们借用净水厂
有了这个
我想可以开始享受这个整合包有趣的部分了
研究算力和玻璃纤维
从量子计算机开始
把它建在这
它的尺寸可以增加到最多 24 个机箱
但现在 6 个就足够了
除了通常的维护问题
这台机器也会有不确定性问题
来解决这些问题
我们必须使用未定元解析器
通过平衡网格中方格的哔哔声强度
接下来给这台机器供电
每个机箱需要 1A UV
还有 1A UV 用于计算机本身
即 7A UV，28A ZPM
所以我们直接使用 64A ZPM 能源仓
一旦我们接上电
启动计算机试试
看起来它仍然无法计算
那是因为我们没有给机箱放入处理器
一旦插入散热器和处理器
开启它
这里可以看到产生了多少算力
以及处理器的热量
在某个时候发生了一些奇怪的事情
我们的 CPU 不知为何融化了
似乎现在配置这台机器的方式变了
暂时
我们不考虑超频
所以只需想好怎么让它工作
我们从一个散热片和一个晶体处理器主机开始
热量迅速上升
但越热散热片工作效率越高
然而
机箱的空间只使用了一半
而我们已经造了整个机箱
所以再加一个散热片和处理器
过了一段时间
看起来温度稳定在处理器可接受的最高温度了
我们甚至没有使用最好的冷却系统
我们可以尝试更好的设置
但现在算力足够了
现在
计算机仅用了供给的四分之一电量
无论如何，我们现在正在产生算力
但它被浪费了
因为没有任何东西连接到光学接口
所以是时候造出利用该算力的第一台机器
研究站
使用它
我们在控制器内放一个闪存
以及在物品固定支架上放待研究物
而现在
我们只需要等待研究完成
我们正在做的研究需要大量算力和电量
经过漫长的等待
我们完成了研究
我们把数据放到装配线的数据库里
这样就可以制作刚刚解锁的新物品
虽然这个新组件非常有用
它并不会真正帮助我们取得任何进展
我们本来要研究聚变 Mk-III 的
但正确的路径可能是
开始做一些高级生物化学
我们从制造新的机器开始
生产一些琼脂
另一条产线产生糠
为了得到所需的植物、肉和骨头
我们用一下珠海渔场
现在我们有了材料
可以用这些东西培养出一些杂菌
把这些平凡的细菌搬入超净间
在那儿使用生物实验室
在培养皿中分离不同种类的细菌
要使用这些培养基
需要把培养皿放在培养缸里
使细菌繁殖
细菌培养缸有两个主要机制
才能以最佳效率工作
就是控制细菌数量和辐射水平
因为我们想以低成本大量制造细菌
我们使用共用放射仓的培养缸
另一个机制是我们希望保持输出仓半满
来最大化细菌生长
为此，我们使用一个覆盖板
一旦仓室达到半满
将打开泵来提取过量的新细菌
为了快速完成所有培养缸的配置
我们可以使用覆盖版复制/粘贴工具
随着培养缸的底座完成
我们补全它的其他部分
另一个问题是
要在细菌生长过程中保持缸内辐射水平恒定
我们会耗尽放射性物质
在这个阶段，我们使用铋
它不仅存量充足，提供时间也长达三分钟
但是对于后期
我们将使用硅岩之类的东西
它只能持续 8 秒
并且是我们不想浪费的材料
所以为了避免浪费放射性物质
我们将只在其他输入仓都存满了材料
再输入放射性材料
在后期，产线规模会变大
虽然材料会变得更贵
却也会更容易耗尽
现在一切都准备好了
我们可以开始培养细菌
最初
它们需要从培养皿中扩散
一旦它们开始在机器内部生长
细菌有的越多，繁殖得越快
直到机器内部的空间变得过于拥挤
在他们开始挨饿之前
红石电路会触发泵来抽取多余细菌
下一阶段将是
把那些正常的细菌和其他东西一起喂给进化过度的细菌
这将产生原始生长催化剂培养基
但是这些细菌的繁殖速度很慢
为了让它繁殖得更快
我们先用一个 LV 输入仓来存储液体
再替换成更大的输入仓
进行更精细的监控
有了这个
我们有了制造干细胞所需的液体
扫描它，获取制作神经处理单元的研究成果
同时，使用大量昂贵的材料
我们开始准备能够承载生命的电路板
它们也是神经处理器的一部分
既然我们需要很多这样的东西
为了加快这个过程
我们可以使用专用的进阶装配线
它的本质上和装配线没两样
但它会在完成上一次制作前开始下一次制作
然后我们做了一套新的电路装配线
来制作湿件电路
在这里，研究站开始发挥作用
因为需要它来制作湿件主机
这是比上次更快的研究
有了这个
我们可以开始建造新一级电路板了
UHV 等级的湿件处理器主机
火速投产，制作 UV 力场发生器
用于聚变反应堆 Mk-III
但是再一次
聚变 Mk-II 的速度在拖我们后腿
所以我们在等待的时候找点别的事做
从准备镅掺杂的晶圆开始
它只需要一点点镅
但处理时间极长
另一件可做的事情是收集些神秘水晶
这是目前的采矿速度
这就是精金合金板和量子护腿给我带来的自信
接下来我们可以去打几个 boss
比如混沌守卫
它们将掉一些未来有用的材料
看来击杀这个 boss 导致了一些奇怪的事情发生
在破坏了这个岛之后
我们脚底抹油
一路到达冥王星
我们在这驯服太空狗失败
它在地牢里藏了张火箭设计图
这次我们要扫描这个示意图
这将产生一种创建它的副本的方法
因为我们不仅仅只需要一份图纸
同时
我们的镅掺杂的单晶硅准备好了
为此，我们可以用五级水来切割它
我们将使用这些晶圆
慢慢做量子功率集成电路
这是即将到来的反应堆所必需的
现在只剩下一件要完成的事情
镅
在等待的时候
我们可以建几个 PCB 工厂
这将使生产电路板比起大化反时的大大降价
至少是在它能超频和并行时
暂时的
它将在 ZPM 电压下以 22 EU/t 运行
我们甚至可以以速度为代价获得额外的输出
这就是第二个 PCB 工厂的用途
用来制备更昂贵的电路板
但它仅仅会在
我们在下一阶段做生物电路板时有影响
而现在
在等待剩余的镅时
我们可以欣赏几场日落
但那对我们帮助不大
所以我想是时候放弃我们的铟了
做我们一集前就该做的事
做第二个聚变反应堆 Mk-II
现在与其花费无法忍受的时间
只需要很长很长的时间
我们可以去欣赏更多的日落了
经过漫长的等待
我们终于完成了新的聚变反应堆
一旦完成充能，它就会开始大量制造镅
但是这个配方有一个小问题
我们得到的不是镅而是镅等离子体
为了得到镅
我们要么消耗电力通入真空冷冻机来制备
或者用略显麻烦的热交换机
或者让等离子体通过多方块涡轮
将镅以副产形式输出
然而镅等离子体具有巨大的能量密度
这意味着转换会相当慢
除非我们用巨大流量的巨大涡轮
但我们还是受到动力仓的限制
不管怎样
我们在这一集中学到了什么？
在游戏初期必须烧大量的钍燃料棒
这样我们就不会因为缺少镥而陷入困境
有了这个
我想我们可以结束这一集了
拜拜
（拥有更多并行）